# A. F. M. MINHAZUR RAHMAN

mrsaurov.github.io | cse.ruet.ac.bd/mrsaurov

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a Computer Science and Engineering graduate from RUET, Bangladesh, where I graduated with first class honors (first position). Currently, I serve as an Assistant Professor at the same institution. My research focuses on deep learning, particularly in computer vision tasks such as segmentation and classification. I am passionate about contributing to advancements in computer vision, a field I believe will significantly shape the future.

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Medical Image Analysis

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science | Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) 2021 Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology (RUET) Rajshahi, Bangladesh CGPA: 3.89 (out of 4.00), Department Position: 1st Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC) | Science 2015

Rajshahi College **GPA: 5.00 (out of 5.00)** 

Secondary School Certificate (SSC) | Science 2013

Rajshahi, Bangladesh

Shiroil Govt. High School Rajshahi, Bangladesh

**GPA: 5.00 out of (5.00)** 

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

**Assistant Professor** September 2023 – Present Department of CSE, Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology Rajshahi, Bangladesh Lecturer December 2021 – September 2024 Rajshahi, Bangladesh Department of CSE, Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology March 2021 – December 2021 Rajshahi, Bangladesh

Department of CSE, North Bengal International University

#### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

# **Published Book Chapters**

• A. F. M. Minhazur Rahman and Boshir Ahmed. "Hyperspectral Image Classification Using Factor Analysis and Convolutional Neural Networks." In Mohammad Shamsul Arefin, M. Shamim Kaiser, Anirban Bandyopadhyay, Md. Atiqur Rahman Ahad, and Kanad Ray, editors, *Proceedings of the* International Conference on Big Data, IoT, and Machine Learning, pages 129–139, Singapore, 2022. Springer Singapore.

#### **Accepted Book Chapters**

• A. F. M. Minhazur Rahman and Md. Ali Hossain. "Deep Learning Approach to Brain Tumor Segmentation from MRI Images." Accepted and presented at the International Conference on Big Data, IoT, and Machine Learning: BIM 2023. Currently under editing for publication in a Taylor & Francis book.

## **Published Conference Papers**

- **A. F. M. Minhazur Rahman** and Md. Ali Hossain. "Attention-refined U-Net with Skip Connections for Effective Brain Tumor Segmentation from MRI images." In 2023 26th International Conference on Computer and Information Technology (ICCIT), pages 1–6, 2023.
- Kowshik Deb Nath, **A. F. M. Minhazur Rahman**, and Md. Ali Hossain. "An Attention-based Deep Learning Approach to Knee Injury Classification from MRI Images." In 2023 26th International Conference on Computer and Information Technology (ICCIT), pages 1–6, 2023.

#### **Accepted Conference Papers**

 Noman Amin, Anwar Hossain Efat, A. F. M. Minhazur Rahman and S. M. Mahedy Hasan. "Enhanced Skin Lesion Detection Using Concatenated DenseNet and Multi-Attention Mechanisms." Accepted for presentation at the 4th Internation Conference on Innovations in Science, Engineering and Technology (ICISET), 2024.

#### RESEARCH PROJECTS

## Brain Tumor Segmentation Using Effective Deep Learning Approach

A research project financed by University Grants Communication (UGC), Bangladesh and RUET

2022-23

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

#### Attendance Manager | Java

An Android app for taking class attendance, keeping track of student and generating attendance report.

Available on Github: Link

#### Med Organizer | Java

An Android application for keeping track of medication, setting reminders, keeping doctor appointment notes, etc.

Available on Github: Link

#### C-Like Compiler | C, Flex, Bison

Compiler for programming lanuguage similar to C that generates MIPS assembly code.

Available on Github: Link

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### Student of the Year - 4th Year

Awarded for outstanding result in 4th year with average 3.97 GPA and academic excellence.

#### Student of the Year - 3rd Year

Awarded for outstanding result in 3rd year with average 3.93 GPA and academic excellence.

#### Student of the Year - 1st Year

Awarded for outstanding result in 1st year with average 3.94 GPA and academic excellence.

## Board Scholarship, Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)

Awardee of the Rajshahi board scholarship in general grade

#### **SKILLS**

- Machine Learning Libraries: TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch
- **Programming Languages**: Python (advanced), C++ (intermediate), Java (advanced)
- Version Control: Git
- Languages: Bangla (Native), English (Professional)

# REFERENCES

# • Dr. Md. Ali Hossain

Professor

Department of Computer Science & Engineering Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology Email: ali.ruet@gmail.com, ali.hossain@cse.ruet.ac.bd

# • Dr. Md. Al Mamun

Professor

Department of Computer Science & Engineering Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology Email: almamun00350@gmail.com, a.mamun@cse.ruet.ac.bd